<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Documentation>
  <AnalyzeCSharp>
    <!-- All -->
    <metadata name="IsResult" type="bool">
      By default only certain symbols are processed as part of the initial
      result set (such as those that match the specified predicate). If this value is <c>true</c>, then this
      symbol was part of the initial result set. If it is <c>false</c>, the symbol was lazily processed later
      while fetching related symbols and may not contain the full set of metadata.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="WritePath" type="FilePath">
      A write path is generated for each symbol during code analysis and serves several purposes. First, it's
      used to automatically create hyperlinks for references in XML documentation comments. It can also be used
      for generating inbound links from other modules or pipelines to a given symbol. Because the WriteFiles module
      will check for any WritePath metadata values when outputting documents, this metadata also makes writing
      symbol documents to disk easier (presumably after they've been sent through a templating module).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="RelativeFilePath" type="FilePath">
      Same as <c>WritePath</c>. This metadata key is available for compatibility with other modules.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="RelativeFilePathBase" type="FilePath">
      Same as <c>WritePath</c> without the file extension. This metadata key is available for compatibility with other modules.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="RelativeFileDir" type="DirectoryPath">
      Same as the directory of <c>WritePath</c>. This metadata key is available for compatibility with other modules.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="SymbolId" type="string">
      A unique ID that identifies the symbol (can be used for generating folder paths, for example).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Symbol" type="ISymbol">
      The Roslyn <c>ISymbol</c> from which this document is derived. If the document represents a namespace, this metadata might contain more than one
      symbol since the namespaces documents consolidate same-named namespaces across input code and assemblies.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Name" type="string">
      The name of the symbol, or an empty string if the symbol has no name (like the global namespace).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="FullName" type="string">
      The full name of the symbol. For namespaces, this is the name of the namespace. For types, this includes
      all generic type parameters.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="QualifiedName" type="string">
      The qualified name of the symbol which includes all containing namespaces.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="DisplayName" type="string">
      A display name for the symbol. For namespaces, this is the same as <c>QualifiedName</c>. For types, this is
      the same as <c>FullName</c>.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Kind" type="string">
      This is the general kind of symbol. For example, the for a namespace this is "Namespace" and for a type this is "NamedType".
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="SpecificKind" type="string">
      The more specific kind of the symbol ("Class", "Struct", etc.) This is the same as <c>Kind</c> if there is no more specific kind.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="ContainingNamespace" type="IDocument">
      The document that represents the containing namespace (or null if this symbol is not nested).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="ContainingAssembly" type="IDocument">
      The document that represents the containing assembly (or null if this symbol is not from an assembly).
    </metadata>
    
    <!-- Symbol specific -->
    <metadata name="MemberTypes" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for namespace and type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all member types. It only
      contains direct children (as opposed to all nested types).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="MemberNamespaces" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for namespace symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all member namespaces. The
      collection is empty if there are no member namespaces.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="ContainingType" type="IDocument">
      This is available for type, method, field, event, property, and parameter symbols and contains a document representing the containing
      type (or <c>null</c> if no containing type).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="BaseTypes" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all base types (inner-most first).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="AllInterfaces" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all implemented interfaces. The collection
      is empty if the type doesn't implement any interfaces.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Members" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all members of the type, including inherited ones. The collection
      is empty if the type doesn't have any members.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="DerivedTypes" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all types derived from the type. The collection
      is empty if the type doesn't have any derived types.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="ImplementingTypes" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for interface symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all types that implement the interface. The collection
      is empty if no other types implement the interface.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Constructors" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all constructors of the type. The collection
      is empty if the type doesn't have any explicit constructors.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="TypeParameters" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type and method symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent all generic type parameters of the type or method. The collection
      is empty if the type or method doesn't have any generic type parameters.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Accessibility" type="string">
      This is available for type, method, field, event, and property symbols and contains the declared accessibility of the symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Parameters" type="IDocument">
      This is available for method and property (I.e., indexer) symbols and contains a collection of the documents that represent the parameters of the method or property.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="ReturnType" type="IDocument">
      This is available for method symbols and contains a document that represents the return type of the method (or <c>null</c> if the method returns <c>void</c>).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="OverriddenMethod" type="IDocument">
      This is available for method symbols and contains a document that represents the method being overridden (or <c>null</c> if no method is overriden by this one).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Type" type="IDocument">
      This is available for field, event, property, and parameter symbols and contains the document that represents the type of the symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="DeclaringType" type="IDocument">
      This is available for type parameter symbols and contains a document that represents the declaring type of the type parameter.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Attributes" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;IDocument&gt;">
      This is available for type, method, field, event, property, parameter, and type parameter symbols and contains the type symbol documents for attributes applied to the symbol.
    </metadata>

    <!-- Documentation (not present for external symbols) -->
    <metadata name="CommentXml" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the full unprocessed XML documentation comments content for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Example" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the rendered HTML content from all <c>example</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Remarks" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the rendered HTML content from all <c>remarks</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Summary" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the rendered HTML content from all <c>summary</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Returns" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the rendered HTML content from all <c>returns</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Value" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      the rendered HTML content from all <c>value</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Exceptions" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;ReferenceComment&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all <c>exception</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol with their name, link, and/or rendered HTML content.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Permissions" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;ReferenceComment&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all <c>permission</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol with their name, link, and/or rendered HTML content.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Params" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;ReferenceComment&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all <c>param</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol with their name, link, and/or rendered HTML content.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="TypeParams" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;ReferenceComment&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all <c>typeparam</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol with their name, link, and/or rendered HTML content.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="SeeAlso" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;string&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all <c>seealso</c> XML documentation comments for this symbol with their rendered HTML link (or just name if no link could be generated).
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="Syntax" type="string">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a generated syntax example for the symbol.
    </metadata>
    <metadata name="[ElementName]Comments" type="IReadOnlyList&lt;OtherComment&gt;">
      This is available for documents in the initial result set (<c>IsResult</c> is <c>true</c>) and contains
      a collection of all custom XML documentation comments with a particular <c>[ElementName]</c> for this symbol with their rendered HTML content and any attributes they contain.
    </metadata>
  </AnalyzeCSharp>
</Documentation>